Finding Aid for Clarence T. Johnston Papers, 1888-1941
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Work Photos (Engineering and Surveying Projects)
  - Building Demolition Undated
    - (Building shell, implosion in progress) (Box 8:2)
      [2015]
  - Reservoirs circa 1897
    - Lower Lake Colorado Reservoir (Box 8:2)
      [2016]
    - Colorado Dam Pool Reservoir (Box 8:2)
      [2017]
    - Buffalo Spring, Yellowstone National Park Fountain Geyser Basin (Box 8:2)
      [2018]
    - Consolidated or Marlin Reservoir (Box 8:2)
      [2019]
    - Big Horn Reservoir Site (Box 8:2)
      [2020]
    - On road between Little & Big Goose Creeks, in the midst of the Big Horn Forest Reserve (Box 8:2)
      [2021]
    - Big Goose Valley taken from ridge on trail up Cross Creek (to E of Creek) looking SW (Box 8:2)
      [2022]
    - Big Goose Creek Valley looking E from W side of Creek near Morrow's Cabins/Big Goose and Beaver and Smiley Ditches on opposite side of valley (Box 8:2)
      [2023]
    - Big Goose and Beaver and Smiley's Ditches near Morrow's Cabins (Box 8:2)
      [2024]
    - Big Goose and Beaver and Smiley's Ditches near (Box 8:2)
    - Morrow's Cabins (Box 8:2)
      [2025]
    - In the count? pasture below Morrow's Cabins (Box 8:2)
    - looking down Big Goose Valley (Box 8:2)
      [2026]
    - Last Chance Reservoir Panorama, 2 plates (Box 8:2)
      [2027-2028]
    - Last Chance Reservoir (Box 8:2)
      [2029]
  - Dome Lake circa 1897
    - Panorama Cloud Park Range from Dome Lake Road, II, III, V, 3 plates (Box 8:2)
      [2030-2032]
    - Dome Lake looking SE from N side (Box 8:2)
      [2033]
    - Dome Lake looking S from N side (Box 8:2)
      [2034]
    - Dome Lake looking SW from N side, 2 plates (Box 8:2)
      [2035-2036]
    - Dome Lake Dam site looking NW from E, 3 plates (Box 8:2)
      [2037-2039]
    - Duck Lake (near Dome Lake) looking SW from N side (Box 8:2)
      [2040]
  - Early Reservoirs and Surveying (5"x7")
    - 1896
      - Stand Pipe, day of test, West Side Mining Co., Routte, Colorado July 1896 (Box 8:2)
        [190]
      - Platte River before entering Canyon September 3, 1896 (Box 8:2)
        [228]
      - Cliffs in Platte Canyon September 3, 1896 (Box 8:2)
        [229]
    - circa 1897
      - Outlet arches from below Reservoir No. 2, Wyoming Development Co. (Box 8:2)
        [2041]
      - Portion of camp construction of Dam Reservoir No. 2, Wyoming Dev. Co. (Box 8:2)
        [2042]
      - Dam Reservoir No. 2 looking northerly, Wyoming Dev. Co. (Box 8:2)
        [2043]
    - 1897
      - Dome Lake August 19, 1897, 3 plates (Box 8:2)
        [380, 383-384]
      - Arant's? 15 miles W of Otto August 22, 1897 (Box 8:2)
        [389]
      - Messrs. Hay, Mear, Nettleton, Johnston at Franoks? after losing the other members August 25, 1897 (Box 8:2)
        [395]
      - Camp on Gooseberry, big tree August 27, 1897 (Box 8:2)
        [398]
      - Camp on Gooseberry August 27, 1897 (Box 8:2)
        [400]
      - Noon camp August 27, 1897 (Box 8:2)
        [401]
      - Camp on Wind River August 29, 1897 Taken morning August 30 (Box 8:2)
        [403]
      - Wind River 5 miles above Dubois, WY August 30, 1897 (Box 8:2)
        [405]
      - Green River camp on W(estern) Pass, August 31 September 1, 1897 (Box 8:2)
        [406]
      - Cart going up a hill on G? September 2, 1897 (Box 8:2)
        [435]
      - Park road through lodge pole pines September 6, 1897 (Box 8:2)
        [415]
      - Bed of a torrential stream on E side, Jackson's Lake September 5, 1897 (Box 8:2)
        [416]
      - Falls on Gibbon River September 8, 1897 (Box 8:2)
        [423]
      - Rapids above Upper Falls September 9, 1897 (Box 8:2)
        [427]
      - Beaver House Lupine Creek September 11, 1897 (Box 8:2)
        [444]
    - 1898
      - Canyon below Shaws Cottonwood Creek June 1898 (Box 8:2)
        [349]
      - Dam site Newells Reservoir, Horse Shoe Creek June 1898 (Box 8:2)
        [353]
      - Newell's Ranch, Horse Shoe Park June 1898 (Box 8:2)
        [354]
      - Dam site MacFarlane Reservoir June 1898 (Box 8:2)
        [357]
    - 1900
      - Warrens Reservoir outlet May 1, 1900 (Box 8:2)
        [514]
      - Looking along Warrens Dam, Cheyenne May 21, 1900 (Box 8:2)
        [517]
      - 1901 (Box 8:2)
      - Flashlight in Cen. Eureka Mine 7/2/1901 (Box 8:2)
        [2044]
      - Cable conveyor, Cen. Eureka Mine, Eureka Utah July 2, 1901 (Box 8:2)
        [2045]
      - Lyman, King, and Johnston July 2, 1901 (Box 8:2)
        [2046]
        (End of 5"x7")
  - Trip To Egypt 1901-1902
    - (Hotel interior) (Box 8:2)
      [2047]
    - (Hotel? exterior) (Box 8:2)
      [2048]
    - (River scene with water carriers) (Box 8:2)
      [2049]
    - (Riverside and water carriers) (Box 8:2)
      [2050]
    - (Group of women water carriers) (Box 8:2)
      [2051]
    - (Two team of oxen and tenders) (Box 8:2)
      [2052]
    - (Group of men sitting by corn harvest) (Box 8:2)
      [2053]
    - (oxen teams pulling threshers) (Box 8:2)
      [2054]
    - (View of creek) (Box 8:2)
      [2055]
    - (Water buffalo in river) (Box 8:2)
      [2056]
    - (River ferry) (Box 8:2)
      [2057]
    - (Flat barge on river with water jugs) (Box 8:2)
      [2058]
    - (Riverside huts) (Box 8:2)
      [2059]
    - (Workers at a quarry) (Box 8:2)
      [2060]
    - Looking SE from road near Gizeh, Nile in foreground, Island of Rhoda and Old Cairo in distance December 12, 1901 (Box 8:2)
      [9]
    - Along road to Gizeh looking N from opposite Gizeh Zoological Gardens [Lebeck trees] December 12, 1901 (Box 8:2)
      [12]
    - Looking W from headgate Menufrijeh? canal toward Rosetta Barrage December 14, 1901 [I5] (Box 8:2)
    - Snapshot of boat on Nile bet. Cairo and Barrage, boat going upstream along eastern margin of the Nile December 14, 1901 (Box 8:2)
      [16]
    - Periphery of sakiyeh on spot where Moses was found. December 18, 1901 (Box 8:2)
      [25]
      (Rim. The stone jars used on the sakiyeh are plainly shown in this picture. They are tied to the wheel and are especially made for this purpose.)
    - Sphinx and Cheops December 19, 1901 (Box 8:2)
      [36]
    - Second pyramid from point N of Cheops December 19, 1901 (Box 8:2)
      [40]
    - Sphinx and Cheops December 19, 1901 (Box 8:2)
      [46]
    - Cheops from NW December 19, 1901 (Box 8:2)
      [47]
    - Arab village W. Island of Balut December 23, 1901 (Box 8:2)
      [69]
    - Clover fields., with buffalo feeding. Arab village in distance December 23, 1901 (Box 8:2)
      [70]
    - Site for a Chadaruff on mainland W of Bulak Island December 23, 1901 (Box 8:2)
      [71]
    - Cleansing a small canal S of Medinet. Farsam looking N December 26, 1901 (Box 8:2)
      [81]
    - Cliffs NE bank above Mesteh January 3, 1902 (Box 8:2)
      [86]
    - Old quarries on east bank of Nile at Gebel Silesileh. Loose material is all refuse from the quarries January 6, 1902 (Box 8:2)
      [31]
    - Chadonfs above Matona January 6, 1902 (Box 8:2)
      [92]
    - Cooks landing Gizeh. Natives came to the boats to sell handmade trinkets and sugarcane stalks (Box 8:2)
    - Giraffe, Gizeh Zoo Gardens January 21, 1902 (Box 8:2)
    - Cairo from top of Ghezineh Palace Hotel January 22, 1902 (Box 8:2)
      [138]
    - Man cultivating ground-ancient Egyptian figure, Gizeh Museum January 22, 1902 (Box 8:2)
      [140]
    - Cairo looking SE from top of Ghezineh Palace Hotel January 22, 1902 (Box 8:2)
      [142]
    - Statue of King who built Lake Moeris, Amenhat III, Gizeh Museum January 22, 1902 (Box 8:2)
      [143]
    - Pumps Agr. fair January 22, 1902 (Box 8:2)
      [148]
    - Mohammed Trav. [Dragoman?] Gizeh Zoo Gardens January 22, 1902 (Box 8:2)
      [194]
  - Twin Falls Canal April 1907
    - Twin Falls, Perinne Hotel April 7, 1907 (Box 8:2)
      [2061]
      ((back row 1 to r) C.A. Tush, Twin Falls; R.D. Goodrich, Cheyenne; P.S.A. Bicker, Milner; R.W. Ferris, Twin Falls. (seated front row 1 to r) James Stephenson, Jr., Boise; O.L. Waller, Pullman; C.T. Johnston, Cheyenne)
    - Twin Falls Canal near Cottonwood Creek flume. Tush, Johnston, Stephenson, Waller, Voorhees April 1-9, 1907 (Box 8:2)
      [2062]
    - Shoshone Falls, 3 plates (Box 8:2)
      [2063-2065]
    - Shoshone Falls from S bank. Goodrich in foreground (Box 8:2)
      [2066]
    - Upper Canal below Cedar Draw (Box 8:2)
      [2067]
    - Upper Canal, looking downstream from upper end Cottonwood Creek flume showing also wood retaining wall at further end anchored to basalt (Box 8:2)
      [2068]
    - Upper line and drop at end of low line (Box 8:2)
      [2069]
      (Two on one plate)
    - Wastegate at Cedar Draw, low line (Box 8:2)
      [2070]
    - Wastegate main canal, Sec. 16-10-19 (Box 8:2)
      [2071]
    - Main canal looking downstream, Sec. 22-10-19 (Box 8:2)
      [2072]
    - Main canal looking downstream from wastegate, Sec. 16-10-19 (Box 8:2)
      [2073]
    - Main canal looking upstream from Dry Creek Reservoir (Box 8:2)
      [2074]
    - Main canal looking upstream from first wastegate below Milner (Box 8:2)
      [2075]
    - Main canal headworks.-Spillway and dam from north side river (Box 8:2)
      [2076]
    - Main canal headworks.-Spillway gates from north side river (Box 8:2)
      [2077]
    - Main canal headworks. Upper face gate spillway and headgate main canal (Box 8:2)
      [2078]
    - Main canal headworks. View lower slope dam in north channel from north bank of river (Box 8:2)
      [2079]
    - Main canal headworks.-Gate spillway from south bank river (Box 8:2)
      [2080]
    - Main canal headworks.-Looking along dam from south side river (Box 8:2)
      [2081]
    - Main canal headworks. Looking northerly from south end dam (Box 8:2)
      [2082]
    - Main canal headworks. Looking westerly from island spillway (Box 8:2)
      [2083]
    - Main canal headworks. Lower slope eastern end of dam from south side of river (Box 8:2)
      [2084]
    - Main canal headworks. Lower slope of dam in south channel (Box 8:2)
      [2085]
    - Main canal headworks. Raising device spillway gates (Box 8:2)
      [2086]
    - Main canal headworks. South end of dam from south bank of river (Box 8:2)
      [2087]
    - Headgate lower canal (Box 8:2)
      [2088]
    - Looking along fill at Cedar Draw low line showing fence for lower bank (Box 8:2)
      [2089]
    - Looking down Perinne Creek from Perinne's house (Box 8:2)
      [2090]
    - Low line just above Cedar Draw (Box 8:2)
      [2091]
    - Low line pond formed by dam at Cedar Draw looking downstream (Box 8:2)
      [2092]
    - Lower canal, entrance to Rook Creek syphon (Box 8:3)
      [3000]
    - Lower canal, looking downstream (west from end of Rook Creek syphon) showing concrete retaining wall (Box 8:3)
      [3001]
    - Lower end (west) Rook Creek syphon (Box 8:3)
      [3002]
    - Lower canal, Rook Creek syphon looking westerly (Box 8:3)
      [3003]
    - Blue Lakes from top of cañon above from west where road begins leading down (Box 8:3)
      [3004]
    - Details Cottonwood Creek flume from lower side, upper canal (Box 8:3)
      [3005]
    - Division Gates lifting device, upper and lower canals (Box 8:3)
      [3006]
    - Division Gates upper and lower canal looking downstream from SE bank, headgate lower canal on right (Box 8:3)
      [3007]
    - Division Gates upper and lower canals, looking downstream from lower bank main canal (Box 8:3)
      [3008]
    - Drop at end of low line (with camera) (Box 8:3)
      [3009]
    - Drop below waste gate looking N, Sec. 16-10-19 (Box 8:3)
      [3010]
    - Drop below waste gate main canal, Sec. 16-10-19 (Box 8:3)
      [3011]
    - Dry Creek Reservoir from near canal entrance (Box 8:3)
      [3012]
    - Entrance gates to Dry Creek Reservoir, 2 plates (Box 8:3)
      [3013-3014]
  - Seminole Canñon August 1907
    (Includes sketches of canyon with numbers representing vantage points of photos)
    - August 17, 1907, 12 plates (Box 8:3)
      [1-12]
    - August 19, 1907, 7 plates (Box 8:3)
      [13-19]
    - August 19, 1907 (Box 8:3)
      [20]
      (part of [20] shown in panorama of [21-22]
    - August 19, 1907 (Box 8:3)
      (panorama partly shown in [20]
    - August 19, 1907 (Box 8:3)
      [22]
      (panorama, [20] shows part of cañon wall shown here
    - August 19, 1907 (Box 8:3)
      [24]
      ([23-24] panorama)
    - August 20, 1907, 3 plates (Box 8:3)
      [27-29]
    - August 20, 1907 Panorama, 2 plates (Box 8:3)
      [30-31]
    - August 20, 1907 Panorama, 2 plates (Box 8:3)
      [32-33]
    - August 20, 1907, 3 plates (Box 8:3)
      [34-36]
  - Chrystal Lake 1908
    - General view, Chrystal Lake Reservoir, looking E downstream June 29, 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [2]
    - North shoulder from dam, Chrystal Lake Reservoir, looking easterly downstream June 29, 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3]
    - South should from dam, Chrystal Lake Reservoir, looking SE downstream June 29, 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [4]
    - Dam site Chrystal Lake Reservoir, looking downstream from same point from which [6] was taken June 29, 1908 [5] (Box 8:3)
    - Chrystal Lake Reservoir site, looking upstream from point SW of dam site June 29, 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [6]
    - Chrystal Lake dam October 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3015]
  - Yellowstone National Park and Jackson Lake Area 1908
    - Government Road Shoshone Canyon, Cody May 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3016]
    - General view Norris Basin, Constant in distance August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3017]
    - Downstream Yellowstone Springs Canyon from Artists' Point August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3018]
    - Downstream from Artists' Point August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3019]
    - Cement bridge, Yellowstone River looking upstream August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3020]
    - Cement bridge, Yellowstone River looking upstream August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3021]
    - Yellowstone River looking downstream from below cement bridge August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3022]
    - Yellowstone River looking downstream from cement arch bridge August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3023]
    - Crater Fountain Geyser August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3024]
    - (A spring) August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3025]
    - Camp near Fountain Hotel August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3026]
    - Jackson Lake and Tetons August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3027]
    - Grotto Geyser, Upper Basin August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3028]
    - Grotto Geyser, Upper Geyser Basin August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3029]
    - Giant Geyser Region, Indicator Geyser in view. Upper Geyser Basin, Y.N.P. August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3030]
    - Government Dam, Jackson Lake (two boys on wagon) August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3031]
    - Jackson Lake and Tetons August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3032]
    - Jackson Lake and Mt. Moran August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3033]
    - Jackson Lake and Tetons from point South (of) outlet August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3034]
    - Jackson Lake and Tetons August 1908, 2 plates (Box 8:3)
      [3035-3036]
    - Lower Falls, Y.N.P. August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3037]
    - Lower Falls from Prospect Point August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3038]
    - Just on crest Wind R. Mts. on Snake River drainage, El. 9600 ft. (Box 8:3)
      [3039]
    - New Crater Norris August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3040]
    - Old Faithful August 1908, 2 plates (Box 8:3)
      [3041-3042]
    - Paint Pots, Fountain Geyser Basin August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3043]
    - Turbon Geyser, Upper Geyser Basin August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3044]
    - Wind River near west line Reservation August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3045]
    - Wind River near west line Reservation August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3046]
    - Yellowstone Lake from near Lake Hotel August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3047]
    - Yellowstone Lake near Hotel August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3048]
    - Yellowstone Canyon looking downstream from lower falls August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3049]
    - Yellowstone Canyon looking downstream from Inspiration Point (Box 8:3)
      [3050]
    - Snake River and Mt. Moran August 1908 (Box 8:3)
      [3051]
  - Wheatland Dev. Co. Reservoir No. 2 1909
    - Judge Runer's? auto party 1909 (Box 3:6)
      [3052)
    - Wheatland Dev. Co. Reservoir No. 2 June 4-5, 1909 (Box 3:6)
      [3053]
    - Keeper's house at Res. No. 2 (Box 3:6)
      [1]
    - Main section of the dam, looking NE from the SW end, McGill's temporary outlet on left foreground and keeper's house in center (Box 3:6)
    - Looking NE along dam near keeper's house (Box 3:6)
    - View of reservoir looking NE from near keeper's house (Box 3:6)
    - Looking toward McGills residence from SW end of dam (Box 3:6)
      [5]
    - Outlet gates (Box 3:6)
      [7]
    - View below outlet from top of dam (Box 3:6)
      [8]
    - View from below outlet, camera at "A" view no. 8 (Box 3:6)
  - Chrystal Lake Dam Site 1910
    - Chrystal Lake Dam, Cheyenne Water Works November 1910 (Box 8:3)
      [3054]
    - Chrystal Lake Dam looking downstream, Cheyenne Water Works November 1910 (Box 8:3)
      [3055]
    - Chrystal Lake Dam looking downstream, Cheyenne Water Works November 1910 taken by Justin T. Ringdon (Box 8:3)
      [3056]
    - Looking upstream, taken by Justin T. Ringdon November 1910 (Box 8:3)
      [3057]
  - Unidentified Engineering Projects Undated
    - (Canal) (Box 8:3)
      [3058]
    - (Quarry) (Box 8:3)
      [3059]
    - (Family visitors at quarry) (Box 8:3)
      [3060]
    - (Group of men in front of a rook cliff) (Box 8:3)
      [3061]
    - (Two men by a creek outlet) (Box 8:3)
      [3062]
    - (Auto party with surveying equipment in a field) (Box 8:3)
      [3063]
    - (Two men in a grassy field) (Box 8:3)
      [3064]
    - (Two men seated in a grassy field with surveying equipment) (Box 8:3)
      [3065]
    - (Small ranch) (Box 8:3)
      [3066]
    - (Engineering project), 2 plates (Box 8:3)
      [3067-3068]
    - (Canal gate) (Box 8:3)
      [3069]
    - (Bridge over river) (Box 8:3)
      [3070]
    - (Dam site, 4 plates (Box 8:3)
      [3071-3074]
    - (Canal gate) (Box 8:3)
      [3075]
    - (Dam site) (Box 8:3)
      [3076]
    - (Dam site), 3 plates (Box 8:4)
      [4001-4003]
    - (Engineering project), 11 plates (Box 8:4)
      [4004-4014]
    - Hanover Council steel flume (Box 8:4)
      [4015]
    - Oregon Basin Canals, Fig. 17. This shows portal on east end of 400 ft. tunnel (Box 8:4)
      [4016]
    - (Engineering project) (Box 8:4)
      [4017]
  - Unidentified Photographs of Work-Related Subjects undated
    (negatives in numbered sequence)
    - (Bearded man with buggy at campsite, bearded man may be Prof. Davis) (Box 8:4)
    - (Ferry crossing river) (Box 8:4)
      [10]
    - (Horses fording river) (Box 8:4)
    - (Horseman crossing river) (Box 8:4)
      [13]
    - (View by river) (Box 8:4)
      [14]
    - (View downriver) (Box 8:4)
      [15]
    - (Scrubby landscape with road) [16) (Box 8:4)
    - (scrubby landscape, horse team) (Box 8:4)
      [18]
    - (Scrubby landscape, river in distance) (Box 8:4)
    - (Sod roof prairie house, antler tree in yard) (Box 8:4)
    - (Bearded man with buggy at creekside) (Box 8:4)
    - (River rapids) (Box 8:4)
      [33]
    - (River) (Box 8:4)
      [34]
    - (Mountain view) (Box 8:4)
      [35]
    - (Mountain view with water) (Box 8:4)
    - (Mountain view across body of water) (Box 8:4)
      [38]
    - (Beaded man with pipe fishing) (Box 8:4)
      [391]
    - (Crow Heart Butte) (Box 8:4)
    - (Woman and four children in doorway of prairie home) (Box 8:4)
      [49]
    - (Sod roof prairie house with wood pile) (Box 8:4)
      [50]
    - (Buggy and horse team) [551 (Box 8:4)
    - (Mountain view, road in foreground) (Box 8:4)
      [58]
    - (Mountain view, Grand Tetons) (Box 8:4)
      [63]
    - (Snow-dusted hills with running fence) (Box 8:4)
      [4018]
    - (Running fence, Panorama 1 of 5) (Box 8:4)
      [64]
    - (Mountain view, running fence in foreground, Panorama 2 of 5) (Box 8:4)
      [65]
    - (Mountain view, Grand Tetons, Panorama 3 of 5) (Box 8:4)
      [66]
    - (Mountain view, Grand Tetons, Panorama 4 of 5) (Box 8:4)
      [67]
    - (Mountain view, Panorama 5 of 5) (Box 8:4)
      [68]
    - (Mountain pass) (Box 8:4)
    - (House at foot of mountains) (Box 8:4)
    - (Fence) (Box 8:4)
      [72]
    - (Teton Panorama with clouds), 5 plates (Box 8:4)
      [74-78]
    - (Mountains behind body of water) (Box 8:4)
      [80]
    - (Mountains behind body of water) (Box 8:4)
      [83]
    - (Mountains reflected in water) (Box 8:4)
      [84]
    - (Reflected mountains Panorama), 3 plates (Box 8:4)
      [85-87]
    - (Reflected mountain) (Box 8:4)
      [91]
    - (Bearded man, Prof. Davis? Colorado?) (Box 8:4)
      [94]
    - (Water) (Box 8:4)
      [95]
    - (Lake and mountains Panorama), 4 plates (Box 8:4)
      [96-99]
    - (Bearded man, Prof. Davis?, at campsite) (Box 8:4)
      [101]
    - (Ash near hot springs, deer in distance) (Box 8:4)
      [103]
    - (Ash formations near hot springs) (Box 8:4)
      [104]
    - (Hot springs), 2 plates (Box 8:4)
      [105-106]
    - (Man sitting by ash formation in a body of water) (Box 8:4)
      [107]
    - (Geyser) [1121 (Box 8:4)
    - (Ash formation) (Box 8:4)
      [113]
    - (Hot springs) E1151 (Box 8:4)
    - (Close-up of hot spring) (Box 8:4)
      [116]
    - (Ash-covered landscape) (Box 8:4)
      [117]
    - (Hot springs) (Box 8:4)
      [120]
    - (Rock? formation at water's edge) (Box 8:4)
      [121]
    - (Hot springs), 8 plates (Box 8:4)
      [122-129]
    - (Ash dome over hot spring) (Box 8:4)
    - (Large ash formation at hot spring) (Box 8:4)
    - (Large ash formation) (Box 8:4)
    - (Geyser) [1331 (Box 8:4)
    - (Hot springs) (Box 8:4)
    - (Ash craters) (Box 8:4)
      [137]
    - (Ash formations) (Box 8:4)
      (2 plates)
      [138-139]
    - (River with falls) (Box 8:4)
    - (Waterfall) (Box 8:4)
      [141]
    - (Geysers), 4 plates (Box 8:4)
      [147-150]
    - (Rook formation and geyser) (Box 8:4)
      [151]
    - (Waterfall and gorge) (Box 8:4)
      [152]
    - (Eroded mountainside) (Box 8:4)
      [153]
    - (Waterfall), 2 plates (Box 8:4)
      [156, 159]
    - (Below waterfall) (Box 8:4)
      [163]
    - (Deep gorge) (Box 8:4)
      [164]
    - (River at bottom of deep gorge) (Box 8:4)
      [165]
    - (River), 5 plates (Box 8:4)
      [166-171]
    - (Waterfall) [1741 (Box 8:4)
    - (Lake Panorama), 4 plates (Box 8:4)
      [182-185]
    - (Lakeside) [1871 (Box 8:4)
    - (Road through mountains) (Box 8:4)
      [189]
    - (Dry bed beside river) (Box 8:4)
      [191]
    - (River) (Box 8:4)
      [192]
    - (Rocky cliff) (Box 8:4)
    - (Natural tunnel at river) (Box 8:4)
      [195]
    - (Rocky, scrubby hillside) (Box 8:4)
    - (Hilltop view) (Box 8:4)
      [197]
    - (Mountain view, scrub in foreground) [198) (Box 8:4)
    - (Rocky mountain top) (Box 8:4)
      [199]
    - (Rocky mountain terrain) (Box 8:4)
      [200]
    - (Rocky, scrubby mountains) (Box 8:4)
      [2011]
    - (Scrubby landscape) (Box 8:4)
- Camp Davis Summer Surveying Camp Photos 1911-1928
  The "Camp Davis" series consists of pictures taken at the summer engineering camp held in northern Michigan. The photographs in this series document the staff, students, and camp projects. There are pictures of roll call, swimming period, and mess tents to portray camp life. The geographical area is shown through pictures of new trails and camp sites. Samples of the students' engineering projects include construction of a boat harbor, a storehouse, and a lumber shed. As director of the camp, Johnston frequently used these photographs to illustrate his annual reports.
  - 1911 Session
    - Camp group (Box 9:5)
    - Tents of Prof. Merrick and Mr. Palmer (Box 9:5)
    - Possible campsite, near Butler's on Burt Lake, 2 plates (Box 9:5)
      [3-4]